♫ In the not too distant future
somewhere in time and space
♫ Mike Nelson and his robot pals
♫ Are caught in an endless chase
♫ Pursued by woman whose name is Pearl
♫ An evil gal who wants to rule the world
♫ She threw a few things in her purse
♫ And in a rocket ship she hunts him
♫ All across the universe ♫
- [Pearl] I'll get you!
♫ I'll send him cheesy movies
♫ The worst I can find
♫ He'll have to sit and watch them all
♫ And I'll monitor his mind.
♫ Now keep in mind Mike can't control
♫ where the movies begin or end
♫ He'll try to keep his
sanity with the help
♫ of his robot friends♫
Robot Roll Call--
♫ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes
♫ And other science facts
♫ just repeat to yourself
"It's just a show,
♫ "I should really just relax."
♫For Mystery Science Theater 3000.♫
(doors clanging)
- Hi, there, I'm Mike Nelson here
on the Satellite of Love. We're--
(engine running)
- Hey, man.
Oh, hey Servo.
- What are you saying
I'm short, huh, what?!
- No, I was gonna ask where you'd been.
- Oh, uh, well, I had karate
then I swung by the gym
to lift, because I had some extra time
before picking up my hot
new girlfriend Christie
who will most likely wear her thong
as she clings to me on
the back of my Harley.
Yeah, well, we're gonna make
out in public a little--
- Servo, you look different.
Hey, you've got lifts in
your hoverskirt, don't you?
- Hey, man, watch what
you're saying there, man.
- You do, you have lifts
in your hoverskirt.
((Mike and Crow laugh)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, easy, easy.
- Take it easy.
Tom, I'm afraid you've
got short man's disease.
- What!?
- It's the tendency for
height-challenged males
to over compensate for a
perceived lack of machismo.
- So, what, are you saying I'm short, huh?
- Yeah, I'm afraid that is implicit.
- Man!
- No problem, though, we just
rub a little baby aspirin on--
- No, no!
- And you'll be fine.
- No, no. (cries)
- There, that's better.
- We'll be right back.
- Can I keep my nunchucks?
- We'll see.
- By a shrimp.
- Little baby short man, we'll see.
(theme music)
Well, how's your courageous battle
with short man's disease?
- Oh (laughs) I'm over that.
Turns out I'm not even short. (laughs)
- Right, huh.
- Well, how about your face, Servo,
does your face hurt?
- Uh, no, why?
- 'Cause it's killing me! (laughs)
- Really? Oh, Jeez, I'm sorry, Crow.
I'll have that checked right away.
- Oh, never mind.
- Let's see what Pearl and them want.
- Just ruin my joke, why don't you.
- How nice to see you, Nelkirk,
I only have a moment.
I'm expecting everyone for the ball.
Isn't it marvelous?
Everyone, simply everyone
is invited to my ball
except, um, let's see,
except Michael J. Nelson,
Crow T. Robot, Gypsy, and a Tim Servo.
I'm dreadfully sorry, there
just wasn't enough room.
And as this is my first
ball, why the walls
of this castle fairly hum
with the unearthly presence
of parties past.
Listen.
- (laughs) I'll tell
you love, these canapes
are flying out of here.
I can barely keep up with myself.
- Well, anyway, this ball shall celebrate
the triumphant return of a Forrester
to this dwelling of evil.
- Well, that sounds great, Pearl.
I hope your party's a big success.
When does the ball start?
- Um, oh, in about
two-and-a-half hours ago.
Okay, I'm gonna need you guys to pretend
like you're a part of the party.
I think that will really draw
in the rest of the guests.
So, come on, mingle!
Make it look like you're having fun.
- (laughing theatrically)
What a marvelous anecdote!
So how do you know Pearl?
- Well, she's got me
trapped up here, actually.
- Really? How awful for you. (laughs)
- Say, Mike, you gonna introduce me
to your purple friend, here?
- Don't you dare, Nelson!
- Oh, I say, everyone, everyone,
let's play charades in the
parlor. (laughing theatrically)
- Baby, why you got's to go?
- Cheese, glorious cheese.
- Oh, forget it!
You couldn't mingle your
way out of a wet paper bag
if it was perfect.
- (singing) Lava, lava, lava.
- Brain Guy!
- What?
- You must get ready for the ball.
It might be gonna start soon.
- Thank's anyway, Pearl, but
I'm just gonna stay in tonight.
(doorbell rings)
It worked, everyone,
they're here, everyone!
- This way, Ortega.
I invited Ortega over tonight
to watch "Sliders" in my room.
We won't get in your way.
(Ortega makes noises)
- Oh, thank you, Ortega.
You look ravishing, too.
- Oh, right this way, you guys.
This is Ortega's cousin Stacy
and her boyfriend Brian.
This is Pearl.
(claps hands)
So anyway, we won't get in your hair.
Come on, you guys,
Brian, good to have you.
- Yeah, I hope we won't
disturb you with all the fun
we'll be having.
Okay you kids, you're gonna watch a movie
while Pearl has company.
It's "PumaMan."
And no coming downstairs
during Pearl's party.
- Oh, by the way Pearl, if anyone else
should happen to swing by
just point them back to my room.
Thanks a lot.
- Of course.
- More canapes, jeez,
I'm eating these things
faster than I can turn them out.
Ooh, Junior Mint!
- (laughing theatrically) Aw, crap.
I got bean dip all over
my new silk organza
tuile strapless dotted swiss--
(alarm sounds)
- Oh, no. What else could go wrong?
(doors clanging)
- This corset is fighting me.
They gave themselves such a peppy name.
_ Okay, okay, listen you guys.
An ancient Aztec legend tells of a god
- Yeah, yeah.
- (laughs) who descended
to earth from the stars--
- Oh, you know what,
I've heard this stuff.
- Sorry.
(ominous music)
- [Tom] Wow, the aliens really
cherried out their spaceship.
- Christmas ornaments of the gods!
- Hot bathysphere action.
- (British accent) No
one knows who they were
or what they were doing.
- [Voiceover] I speak to all humanity.
- Can you hear me in the back?
- [Voiceover] With this mask
I will always be with you.
- Oh, that'll be fun!
- [Voiceover] My son
will be its custodian.
As will be the sons of his sons.
- Well, gotta go.
- [Voiceover] Through the
ages he will have the powers
of a Man-God, the powers of a Pumaman.
- And the power of bleach.
- [Voiceover] The Pumaman,
the Pumaman, the Pumaman.
- Now it just sounds funny.
- Now there's a couple
of Aztec names for you!
(exotic music)
- Oh, the Pu-MAY-mun.
- Copyright 1462, what is that?
- I think you need to
study your Roman numerals.
- Tonight, on a very special
"Touched by a Pumaman" ...
- And the little hand towels
are for our guest star.
- Yeah, a bunch of hairy
guys in thongs sat down
and wrote a screenplay.
- With Randall "Tex" Cobb as "the Mask."
- Oh, he's the consiglieri of this film.
- (Italian accent) And-a my
paisano, Michael Billingsley.
- At least this movie
will have nice shoes.
- Back, back, back, it's a home run!
- Well, someone seems to have gilded you
and that's what's causing
your skin problems.
- Uh, I can't help but feel
that you're staring at me.
- [Tom] Die, aunt, die!
- [Crow] There's something
wrong with this mirror.
- Well, Jane--
- Are you getting serious?
- [Man] Do you think you can decipher it?
- If you need your toast buttered, ma'am,
I'm your man.
- Yes, it's an Aztec
inscription about a man
with the blood of a god in his veins
who comes from outer space.
- Georgette Relicopter.
- A Pumaman.
- [Mike] I guess what I meant was,
are you gonna type those letters?
- I also serve as a napkin holder, ma'am,
if you need that.
- Please, continue.
- It's fascinating.
- It's a curse.
- It says the f-word.
- Are they all trying to make weight?
- Whoever desecrates the Puma god image
will in turn be destroyed
by the living Pumaman.
- That's ridiculous, it's just a legend.
- [Tom] I'm confused, not happy.
- Sometimes there is more truth in legend
than in history.
- And there's more salt
in ham than in turkey.
- So the curse can strike you, too.
- I always prefer to strike first.
- [Crow] Oh, I hope that
striking first thing
works out real good for you.
- Oh, idol's got a fanny pack.
- Intel inside.
- (gasps) Incredible!
A 3000-year-old find which
conceals unthinkable technology!
- We gotta hire a brunette.
- But this is proof of
an outer space presence
in our history.
- She said that about waffles.
- It's an incredible discovery!
- An egg! Oh, it's Donald Pleasence.
- We must inform the press.
- That is not for you to decide.
- That's Cheryl Ladd's department.
- You can't hide this.
- Who is to prevent me?
- A halfway smart guy
with muscles and hair?
- Miss Dobson--
- Could you gift wrap this for us?
Hit me with your best slap-shot.
- Your mind--
- Did you put an aspirin in my Coke?
- And your will--
- Oh, the control the will game again.
- Belong to me!
- I have a receipt!
- Forever!
- I think controlling
her will might involve
sloe gin and a Trans Am.
- Uh-oh! Did somebody put
unleaded in this thing?
- This is what it's like
when I put my contacts on
inside out.
- Hey, telekinetic book dumping.
- Go now and obey.
- Get me a soda pop and a Caramello.
- It's S&M day at the field museum.
- Oh, lemme try, lemme try!
- Who did we get this from?
Is there a card with this?
- Oh, is half-time over?
What's the score over there?
(mysterious music)
- I am the supermodel of Christmas past.
- He's basically an old baby.
- We make slaves of men with this mask.
- And we'll rule fish, too.
- We'll dominate the world.
Who can stop us?
- With my brains and your beauty.
- The Pyoo-ma-man.
- Poo-ma-man, actually.
- We must find him.
- Then we'll lock him in a pet taxi.
- And kill him.
- Or send him a cease-and-desist letter.
(dramatic music)
- AUGGH! Hey, look, Big Ben, AUGGH!
- We're downsizing, Steve.
- The Greg Louganis London special.
- Call our 900 number and vote!
(tranquil music)
- The new Big Bird actionwear.
I'm supposed to be in bio-lab.
- (sniffs) How much patchouli do you need?
- Ted Cassidy in his
most sensitive role yet.
- He's got a great butt. (hums)
- This is where Cher
stores her discarded ribs.
- Mr. Farms!
- I'm Bernie Kopell.
- Yes sir, I know.
I must not mistake this museum for a gym.
- Ah, you're well aware of that, are you?
- Yes, and I'm also aware I'm not supposed
to work out during museum hours.
- And now a word from my sponsor.
- What's the matter, you sick?
- No, I get this way when I sense danger.
- Or when I eat a sack of White Castles.
- Well, you sense rightly.
You're in danger of being fired!
- I don't care.
I'll work in my uncle's
natural history museum
down the block.
- [British accent]
You-you-you non-British guy.
(theme music)
- Fluffy seems to be eating less and less
and getting thinner and thinner.
- Man, who am I kidding,
I can't build a cat.
- A sweater that says,
"I've read the works of Alan Alda."
- I'm looking for something in a bone,
maybe a femur.
Pelvis, sack of patellas maybe.
(tense music)
- You're not gonna pour molten
gold down my throat, are you?
- All right, pencils down class.
- The dry look, from Gillette.
- Uh-oh, shoplifting a
hip bone for his grandma.
- Yeah, this is why 7-11s allow no more
than three Aztecs at one time.
- I'm gonna tell Mr. Weatherby.
(tense music)
- Hey, hey that was my scapula!
I just took it out to air dry!
- Now he takes out a personal ad.
"Saw you in museum, you took bone,
I chased you."
(all laugh)
- Oh, hey, sorry!
- I'm fine.
I used up a perfectly good
pants-wetting for that.
- How am I ever gonna get back in there?
This is hopeless.
I should just go home.
- Yep, he can sense danger.
A post-it note can sense
danger better than this guy.
- I'll duck into Willa
Cather's ancestral home.
(tinny music)
- Is that "If I were a
rich man" on harpsichord?
- I believe it was.
- I'm still not sensing danger.
- Is this about the pens I took?
You're the guy who's
been writing anti-Aztec
stuff on the bathroom walls?
- Anthony Robbins!
- You are the Pumaman.
- Actually he's John Davidson-man.
- Just gonna edge the
lawn real quick, here.
- This always happens.
People throw me out the window,
tell me I'm Pumaman, then leave!
- Uh, (clears throat) Hear my mighty roar!
Grr?
- I'm gonna tell my boss I'm Pumaman.
Maybe he'll let me off early.
- Pumaman. I sure hope
we don't see this guy
go into heat at some point.
(Mike makes gagging noise)
Sorry.
- Professor Farms?
- Where are the Faye Dunaway auditions?
- Did your new dinosaur get away?
- No, but he sure looked like one.
- You're hunting him down with that club.
- Look, I don't have any change.
Leave me alone.
- Um, tell me, are we meeting in a dream?
- I don't think so.
- Then it's really true, I
fell from the third floor.
- And my hair looks great!
- Aren't you hurt?
- No, just a little confused.
- Hey, a see-through hat!
- My name's Jane Dobson, and
I'd like to come talk to you
about a brief thesis on the Mesozoic era.
- Well, if you're asking
me how flying relates
to man's evolution, I don't know.
(Jane laughs)
- We're a fun couple, aren't we?
- Do we have to discuss this here?
- Is that a proposition?
- Yecch.
- No, it's an invitation
to my house tonight.
My father's having a
couple of friends over
and I was wondering if you could join us.
I've got all my books there
and it would be easier.
This is the address.
- Oh, wait, that's my
recipe for olive loaf.
- An invitation to the Dutch Embassy?
- Does that scare you?
- Uh-huh.
- Dutch are mean.
- Well, try to overcome it.
My father's the Ambassador.
- Okay. I'll even bring
my ceremonial club.
(Jane laughs) Come anyway
you like, but come.
- Now that's gotta be a proposition!
- See you tonight? 9 o'clock?
- Someone will show you
where to park the cars.
- Zubaz top and a lab
coat and a veil, it works!
- And this is from the
"missing persons" collection.
- (deep voice) I am a wood sprite.
- Is she in mourning for her turtle?
Is that why the hat?
- (Tom sings) Dum-ba-ba-ba-bum-ba-bum.
Mentos, the fresh-maker.
- I've reconsidered.
I don't want you to come to my party.
- I've contacted Tony Farms.
There's a high probability it's him.
- Did you carry out my orders?
- Yes, sir.
- He'll come to my house
for dinner tonight.
- I don't have to listen to that!
- We got our paychecks in today, sir.
- Everything coincides, sir.
It looks like we found the right man.
- Fine, Rankin.
I do hope so.
If only for the sake of the others.
- I hope to be as bald
as you someday, sir.
- Well, we'd better
sponge out our outfits.
(inaudible) if you wanna hang around.
- Well, get over here and pick out a wig
and let's go trick-or-treating.
- Pleasence-mobile away!
- Listen to me, Dobson.
Everything is as planned for this evening.
But there is one slight alteration.
- The party tray is coming from Subway.
- I shall be at your house myself.
- Why would you have a bust
of Ron Ely in your home?
- Dismiss the servants.
I don't want any strangers interfering.
- That's kind of a noticeable
tic. (makes throat noises)
- Parachute slash bowtie.
- What! Damn clapper!
- David Birney is the Aramis
man in "Wait Until Dark."
(ominous noise)
- There's cherry Kool-aid
in my saline bottle.
(ominous music)
- Wanna see the pictures?
Your boudoir shots turned out great!
- Now plunger him senseless!
- No one interrupts my prom preparations.
Every room in this hotel
comes with an Aztec.
- You see in the dark.
You fall like a cat.
You are the Pumaman.
- No, I'm a madman and
I'll smash your head in
if you take one more step.
- Pumaman does not kill my people.
- He doesn't, but I do,
now get out of here!
- You can chase me away, but
not the blood in your veins.
Your father saw in the dark.
Your father jumped in the air.
Your father protected my people.
- My father was a physician.
The only people he
protected were his patients.
- A doctor here, but a great Pumaman
in the Andes plateaus.
- Oh, yeah, he was for a couple years!
- You're a crazy criminal,
but this is the last time
you go around throwing
people out of windows.
- Before you call the police--
- Caress.
- Look.
- I'm a representative of Aztechnologies.
- Definite proof that he
has a copy of that picture!
- You were only a boy at the time.
- Then you were a girl,
and then you were a boy again.
- I did not need to kill to find you.
- I kill for fun.
- Who are you, anyway?
- My name is Vadinho.
- I'm an onion.
- I'm the high priest
of the temple of the god
who came from other worlds.
- What do you want from me?
- I came to give you this.
- Woah, hey!
- It belonged to your father.
With this you will have
all the powers he did.
- Or your money back.
- I will teach you to use them.
Put it on.
- You're nuts!
- I said, "Put it on!"
- The hell with putting it on!
- Can you imagine me
showing up at the Dobson's
wearing something like that?
- Look what you're wearing now, I mean--
- I say put it on--
- And you say, "Pyoo it oon."
- And you put it on.
- Okay, pal, okay, take it easy.
- Man, I hate it when
Aztecs force themselves
into your hotel room and
make you try on belts.
- I know, nothing worse.
- (Deep voice) Wow, look at
all the Farrah Fawcett posters!
- Hey, where's your phone?
I wanna check my Aztec messages.
(doors clanging)
- Come in nanites!
- Hey, Spike, what are you doing?
- Oh, I'm gonna get a hair
appointment with the nanites.
I'm thinking of getting that dry look,
like the guy in the Puma movie.
- Mike, your sense of style,
as always, is unerring.
Go for it, you turkey!
- Hi, can I help you?
- Oh, yeah, I had a hair
appointment for now.
- Oh, hi, Mike!
Are we gonna do the
same as last time, or--
- Ooh, well, hi, Shelley.
No offense, but, you know,
last time you made my hair
like 70 miles high, so I was wondering
if any of the other stylists
were available, you know,
Deca or Jondelle?
- Oh, I see, I understand.
- Great, 'cause, you
know, I don't mean to--
- They're all busy, I just checked.
It's just me.
Now what do you want?
- Uh, well, if I could get the dry look,
if it's not too much trouble (laughs)
- Trouble? Why would it be any trouble?
It's no trouble at all.
So, you got the day off today,
or do you live around here,
or is it pretty nice out this
day, or here, you're done.
The dry look.
- Well, uh, thanks, Shelley,
I hope I didn't offend you.
So sensitive, man.
- Mike, I think she mighta
went just a little too dry.
- Ah, what are you talking about?
I'm sure it's--Ow, ooh!
Well, maybe she went a
little heavy on the mousse,
but (laughs) once I shower
I'm sure it will be fine.
We'll be right back.
- You know, if we could
just redirect a river
on to your head, I think
we could salvage it.
- So you like it?
(theme music)
- Father, I'd like to introduce
you to Professor Farms,
the paleontologist I spoke
so much to you about.
- Welcome, Professor.
- Thank you.
- These are some old guys.
- Sir George Bradley
of the Energy Ministry.
Sir John Forbes-Asquith,
Sir Michael Robinson.
- Minister of Wattles.
- Where's the keg?
(ominous music)
- We're here to pick up our Grammys.
- Um, (clears throat) I'm
afraid I ran over your dog
in the driveway, I'm so sorry.
- My name is Pleasence, and I am funky.
- It's better than when he
wore his little black dress,
I suppose.
- Battle of the Network Eyebags.
- Ah, no, they're gonna start tangoing.
- I'm sorry, this is a "no
English has-beens" party.
- What kind of party clown are you?
I'm not paying for this.
- Yep, Donald "Room-clearer" Pleasence,
- It's my irritable
bowel syndrome, isn't it?
- With Mitchum I can skip a day.
- Sugar-frosted eyes.
- I was supposed to bring
an appetizer, wasn't I?
- Well, who's for foosball?
- (laughs) Another one of my father's
very important friends.
- I thought is was your aunt.
- What's the matter?
- I'm bored.
- I don't know.
I get this way when I
sense some sort of danger.
- Or some sort of breasts.
- With me? (laughs)
What could be dangerous?
- Wearing loose-fitting clothing
around a powered take-off
could be dangerous.
- Your charm, perhaps.
- (laughs) You're not
doing so badly yourself
for a paleontologist.
Well, I'm from the Neanderthal School.
And occasionally my
primitive instincts pop up.
- Wanna go and circle a mammoth later?
- (laughs) You're sounding
much better, Professor.
- You make me feel like
I'm still in the museum.
Why don't you just call me Tony.
- Okay, Tony.
- Let me show you the way out.
Please don't come back.
- This is where I keep all my books.
- So, dinosaurs became extinct because
they no longer knew
how to love each other,
is that correct?
- In a wrong kind of way, sure.
- Exactly.
And I certainly wouldn't want our species
to end in the same way.
- All aboard!
- That's the best biological blackmail
I've ever heard.
- But, Mike, this is called "kissing."
Maybe you could try this
with someone someday.
- Well, thanks, maybe-- Hey!
(Crow laughs)
- I hate your crotch!
- All right, disco fighting!
(makes disco sound effects)
(upbeat music)
- He's totally pounding Eddie Rabbitt.
- Man, the Dutch Embassy neighbors
must always be calling the cops.
- Tiny halls, for the
narrow-shouldered among us!
- We're late for tap class.
- Ironic, he looks like a
waiter, and he's dumb. (laughs)
- Al Pacino's elevator.
- Apparently the house capsized
and he and Shelley Winters
have to climb up through the basement.
- Oh, man, I gotta get that
order out to table six,
why is the kitchen so
far from the dining room?
- He's in a attic, uh, attic,
uh, Attica, Attica, Attica!
- He's gonna write
Pumaman's rules on the wall.
- Thank goodness they made
their house out of peanut brittle.
- So basically a mild rain
could take out that roof.
- Well, it's my favorite
ball, I will not lose it.
- Man, there's a lot of
reindeer crap up here.
- Like an idiot on the roof (sings)
(meows)
- Spends the next three hours
running from edge to edge.
- Tony!
- It's Gino, I've been
lookin' for you, you mook!
- Here, here's a garter snake for you.
- The world's most
persistent belt salesman.
- Lower yourself down with that.
- Put it on!
- Then what?
- Jump!
- I'll be killed!
- Put it on!
- And then get killed.
- You know, my mom had a pair of earrings
that did the exact same thing.
- (laughs falsely) No, I
mean you look great, really!
- Idiot.
- Jump now!
- I'm not a bird.
(theme music)
- Fly!
(upbeat music)
- The first thing he
does is poop on my car.
Look out for the--oh, boy,
right into the propellers.
- I gave him the Captain
Dork costume by mistake.
- ♫ Pumaman, he flies like a moron. ♫
- He has the power to
rear-project major cities.
- Now a bird gets sucked into his engine
and he goes down immediately.
- Hey, they'll find
his black box and hear,
"Duuuhhhh, wooooaaahhh!"
- I hate to be picky,
but pumas aren't really known for flying.
- Look, Twiggy!
- You missed her.
- And he immediately uses
his powers for peeping.
- Thank you.
You do not abandon.
- I kiss my frog in your honor.
- Why don't you give me that belt back?
I'm gonna give it to somebody else.
- Are you convinced now?
- I don't know what's going on.
I'm afraid to move.
- You do not fly, but your mind does.
- Yeah, thanks, Castaneda.
- You are afraid, but the other you isn't.
- The other who?
- Cindy Lou Who?
- Tell me the truth, Vadinho.
Who am I?
- You have the blood of the
gods coming from other worlds.
- Ooh, god-blood is hard to get out.
- You are the Pumaman.
- It's not possible, it's not possible.
- We're out of Triscuits!
- Tremendous leaps.
That wasn't a man, it was a cat jumping.
- Finally we've found him.
- Mr. Right.
- Now the only task is to kill him.
And that's the easiest job of all.
- The hardest job is growing hair.
- Here, have another beer, honey.
- Ooh, I let that freaky
paleontologist kiss me.
His gooey lips were all over me.
(funky music)
We're almost there.
We're about to turn around.
Get ready to go into action.
- Um, good buddy.
- (makes disco sound
effects) Shake it! Shake it!
Driving Donald Pleasence around, yeah,
shake it!
- Huh, Scoliosis-man, here.
- Check, please.
- Now!
- Gods are dragging him by
the elastic in his BVDs.
- Oh, the evil love Silver Shadows.
So Pleasence and his thugs
are just spinning cookies
on a construction site?
- Great, the gods got me
in a holding pattern, here.
- I sense danger.
- Are criminals genetically
drawn to construction sites?
- Whoa, his pants came clean off.
- Don't lose your footing,
I mean flying power!
(funky music)
(gunfire)
- I can see the same thing,
only it's really red.
- Jetsons are flying overhead.
(gunfire)
- Guys, look at me, I'm gonna jump, watch!
Oh, my ankles!
- That's too much mustache,
he's pushing the envelope.
- [Voice on radio] He's disappeared.
We can't see him any more.
- Idiots.
- And get off my lap.
- Get moving, comb the area.
Find him!
Kill him!
- Donald's only use for the word "comb."
We just heard it.
- Sam Elliott is Ted Turner
in "The Gregory Peck Story."
- This is nice, I'm gonna
break out of the racket
and open a little pie place here.
(happy music)
- Yay! Happy music! Whee!
- Let go of me, let go!
- I wanna know where
Kobras is hiding the mask!
- I don't know!
- Tell me or I'll drop you!
You idiot, what do you
think's gonna happen
if you shoot me?
- You'll die!
- Right! Let's see what
would happen to you!
(Man screams)
- Help, I'm falling at a 60 degree angle
breaking all the laws of physics!
- Are you gonna cooperate
or do you wanna end up like the gun?
- Put me down!
- Not until you talk!
- I don't know anything!
I get my orders from Rankin!
- Where's the hideout?
- It's a secret, only a few people know.
- And you're not one of them, right?
Then we have nothing to talk about.
Bye, pal.
(Man screams)
- I'll tell you!
- My mustache makes me fall sideways!
- It's in a mansion,
I swear, in a mansion.
But I don't know where.
No one who's ever been there remembers it.
Really.
Everyone who goes there doesn't talk.
- So no one who doesn't
go there doesn't not talk?
- They can't remember anything.
They can't remember anything, I swear.
I swear.
- Would you stop holding me by my nipples?
- What are you doing?
Don't leave me hanging here!
- Tell me who shot JR?
Come on!
- Come back!
- Ow, the gods are snuggying me!
- Dorf on rituals.
(squelching noise)
He lands in a cow flop with this--?
- They protected you.
- Yeah.
It didn't help me find out
where Kobras is hiding the mask.
It's in a mansion, that's
all I could find out.
- Find.
- What do you mean, find?
You know how many mansions
there are in London?
- Probably like a billion!
- I said "find" and you can find it.
You must learn new powers.
All you do is concentrate.
- Here?
- No, we go home.
- So they can get us?
They'll be waiting there for me.
They're probably worrying
right now because I'm late,
afraid something happened to me.
- Are pumas also known for their whining?
- Follow me.
- I'm gonna kill you over here.
- Pumaman--Liberace with Dockers.
- ♫ Pumaman, when will he find love?
♫ Pumaman♫
(mellow music)
- Look, you call it corn, I call it maize,
we'll never get along.
- That's where I almost lost
my virginity, over there.
- High Plains Weenie.
- What's this supposed to be?
- My refuge.
- It fits your proportions.
- Do you have a small,
whiny warehouse for me?
- If this where you sleep?
- Why don't you kill a
pig here, what is this?
- How do you sleep on that?
- Are you poor, ooh?
- How one sleeps does not matter.
How one wakes up is important.
Kneel!
- Uh, the name's Tony, actually.
- Are you sure they're out
there listening to you?
- Of course.
- And are they powerful?
- Absolutely.
- Then why don't they give us a hand?
- They always do.
Although we do not usually know it.
You know it now.
Kneel!
- Oh, no, Tony, remember, I to--oh, oh.
- Make silence in you.
Leave all material things behind.
- All my fabric?
- Become part of the cosmos.
- (Imitates Carl Sagan) Billions
and billions of Pumamen.
- Concentrate your mind on
the image of the god Puma.
Have you done this, brother?
- I'm sorry, I wasn't listening.
- Yes.
- Good.
Now think hard of that mansion.
Concentrate.
You will find it.
- I can't get the "Pina
Colada" song out of my head.
- And now prepare.
You must take the great trip.
- We're going to Grandma's?
- Dive into the nothingness.
- Watch MTV?
- Return to the surface
where the sacred mask is.
- How is that possible?
- Everything is possible for the mind.
- Well, most minds.
- Concentrate.
You must have faith in
your powers, in your heart.
- In your ropy little arms.
- If you want to, you will travel.
Go!
(Farms breathes deeply)
- No, no, not that kind of go!
- Prepare the effeminate-mobile!
(theme music)
- Yes.
- Hi, guys!
- You are the one, the
gods have picked you!
- You are Coatimundi-Man.
- And it is time to don
your hero's costume.
Your Coatimundi look will inspire fear
in the superstitious criminal mind.
- Okay, well, I'll give
it a whirl, you know,
if I've been chosen and all.
- Evil beware!
Coatimundi-man is born this day!
- Okay, I'll just put on my stuff.
I've got kind of a Rhoda vest going here.
And, ohh, a Dr. Who scarf.
- Yes, and with all the attendant powers
of this majestic Coatimundi.
For instance, um--
- Yeah, yeah, for example, uh--
- Well, you can shoot magnetic
laser beams from your--
From your nose!
- Yes, yes!
And now he is the mighty,
yet mysterious Coatimundi.
- His powers are yours,
it is your destiny.
- Okay, well, you know
what, destiny or not,
you guys, I really had my heart set
on those cold leftover sesame noodles,
so I'll be your mythical hero later.
(simple children's music)
- Wait, don't you hear?
Your inspiring hero's
theme song is playing.
(ratchet sounds)
Oh, and see, the gods
are coming from space
to tell you you must serve
or evil will triumph!
- Wow, I see a beach ball and a string,
and a sting and a pulley.
And there's Gypsy, hey, Gypsy!
- [Gypsy] Hey, Mike, sorry.
- That's all right.
- She's doing the will of the gods!
- Pay no attention to her.
- Well, you know what?
Hey, Gypsy, I really am
gonna grab those noodles,
you wanna split them with me?
- [Gypsy] Yummy, let's go!
- Ow!
- There goes our gods.
- Well, it would appear
that he is not yet ready
to accept his coatimundi nature.
- Yes, and the gods are certainly, uh--
I think gods will be--
Man, they're gonna finish
all the cold sesame noodles!
(alarm sounds)
- Let's go, let's go!
- We're not gonna get any!
(doors clanging)
- You ate all the sesame
noodles, didn't you?
- Yeah, they're all gone.
- Help me, father!
- My homework is really hard!
- Excuse me, coming through.
- Help me, father!
- I need a couple of bucks to make rent.
- Help me, Vadinho!
♫ Help me, Vadinho,
help, help me Vadinho ♫
(Sniffs) They have cats!
Oh, no, that's me.
- Would you take that off?
- Look, just don't use
the holodeck any more
if you don't know how to use it.
- (sighs) Thank you.
- Guy who lives on the second floor.
- You're pretty.
- Did you find it?
- No.
- What are you doing, I
thought you were gonna find it.
It's okay, I just, I thought
you were gonna find it.
- I learned that I can only
project myself to a place
that I know.
I have to know exactly where I wanna go
otherwise I'll get lost into nothingness.
- So it's off to Hooter's.
- Then we are no closer.
- So you whizzed it.
- Listen, Vadinho--
- Are you a kind of onion?
- Is finding the mask the only way?
- Yes. If we do not succeed
terrible things will happen.
- The gods will give you the wet look.
- They have lost their connection.
- The network is down.
- The mask is serving evil.
- Can't they do anything from up there?
- Man is free, man is master of himself.
- Man sounds cool.
- But if they come, man is no longer free.
- Man could get pricy.
- You must concentrate.
You will find the solution in your mind.
- I think we saw the limits of his mind
just a few minutes ago.
- Let's not be roommates any more, okay?
(upbeat music)
- I'm thinking of having
my chin smallened.
- (Tom imitating Gilbert
Gottfried) I'm in the firetruck
for USA Up All Night.
- Soundtrack by my little brother's Casio.
- I keep dreaming of a
little man in a tiny tower.
- Uh, hi.
- Where did you come from?
- Out there.
- What sort of a story's that?
- I'm the Pumaman.
- I mean, who is this guy?
- Who's he, somebody out of a comic strip?
I've never heard of him.
- He didn't materialize until yesterday.
- Well, are you getting
anything out of it?
- Mostly trouble.
- I told you Tony, if you want adventure
why don't you join up with us?
It's all the sports you can take,
high jump, low jump, you get
a free sauna at the end of it.
- I'll keep that in mind, Martin.
But in the meantime, you
wouldn't happen to have
a transmitter and receiver
to lend me, would you?
- You mean a position indicator?
- Yeah.
- Hey, an old donut back here.
- Here's the pacemaker, thanks
for letting me borrow it.
(indicator beeps)
- How does it work?
- The closer you get, the
more constant the bleep.
- Over what range?
- Up to two miles.
- Okay, and if you slow
down, I'll get out.
- You mean here?
- No, I'm going the other way.
- What did you say you do?
The Sandwich-man?
- No, the Pumaman, that's
a whole different bag.
- What are you advertising?
- Men from outer space.
- He is the Pumaman!
He can get out of a car
going three miles an hour.
(door slams)
- The Queen!
(crash)
- (laughs) A steering column
plunged through his chest,
that's great.
- (British accent) Lost control
of me bladder, sorry, mate!
- You have the jaws of life on you?
- (laughs)
- I've a good mind to join
a marching band, you--
- Oh, where am I gonna get
another personal fire truck?
- Oh, I did deserve all
those beatings as a child.
(arrow twanging)
- Cupid!
(tense music)
- Here he comes.
- Light the candles!
- Trying to net some tuna
and we got this thing.
- Call him.
- He's playing with mommy's lipstick.
- Don't come in, Tony, run!
- Eat this baguette, eat it!
(Vadinho screams in pain)
(Tom growls)
- The Pyoo-may-man.
- More ketchup please.
- Don't worry about me, watch out!
- He used his trolling motor on them.
- Ooh, I think he officially bonked them.
- Beat me, fine, but to drape a net on me?
- (whines) And then they snagged on me
and called me "Prince Valiant" and said
I had a stupid fakey religion.
- Don't let them net me.
- Save yourself, disappear.
Please do it.
(funky music)
- Do the Hustle!
- Score, it's good.
- Into this piece of drywall.
- Just doing his floor routine.
- There he is!
(gunfire)
- Ow, ow, ow, I'm dead, okay, ow, ow!
- Molasses!
- I don't see him any
more, (inaudible) anyway.
- I don't think he knows
these guys are here.
He's just playing around them.
(gunfire)
- Whee, this is fun!
- I love the Pyoo-may-man.
- (inaudible) Shoot!
- Yeah, in ten to twelve hours they should
be out of ammo.
- My kapok!
(gunfire)
- I just wanna check your axle here.
- Brake, step on the brakes!
(Men screaming)
- So this lousy movie ruins
a perfectly good Jaguar.
- Hey, what's going on?
- The Archangel Duane.
- Tony, you have power in your hands!
Your hands are claws!
- Sorry I forgot to tell you about that.
- Pumaman can rip through
pure Contact Paper.
(Men shouting)
- I am joining your carpool!
- These poor guys aren't
even the villains.
They just came to get some stuff
out of their U-Stor-It.
- Well, time to drop in on
the Super Bowl at half-time.
- Meanwhile, in Georgy Girl--
- She's driving the cameraman to school.
- Snoopy.
(spring boings)
- Now he gets drunk and pops
into old girlfriend's car.
- Tony, how did you get here?
- Never mind, drive.
- He said.
- But they'll kill you if they find you.
Kobras wants to kill you.
They're following me,
they're right behind me.
- Never mind, tell me where the mask is.
- Get your copy at Blockbuster's.
- Don't ask me that.
I can't.
I swear I'd like to, but I can't.
I'm conditioned to keep the
secret, just like everyone.
I can't do it.
- Try! Fight him!
Fight him with your will!
- But my will won't.
- I-I-can't, he's commanding
me from a distance.
- Amelia Airhead.
- I can't do it.
Tony, help me.
Free me!
Something terrible's happening
to me and to everyone.
Help me, don't leave me.
- A helmet, or a hat, or what the--
- Sorry, we stopped for Slurpees.
- There they are, run!
Run! Save yourself!
- Play your theme music and hop around!
- We now revisit Brideshead
and do a revisiting.
- It's one of Sting's cabins.
- I think she's visiting
Helena Bonham Carter.
- Man, with those boots she has to use
high-altitude baking directions.
(interceptor beeps slowly)
(receiver beeps quickly)
- Mr. McGregor's about to shoot them.
(beeping quickens)
- Uh-oh, he's in d-fib!
Get the crash cart stat!
(constant beep)
- (calming voice) This is a
test of the audience's patience.
- Think we're gonna sell a lot of these.
- Hey, a raccoon.
- Goldfinger's riding with Octopussy.
- I'll go mess up and you save me.
- Meet me in the laboratory.
- And don't ever out-dress me again.
- I don't believe you
guys mooned us back there.
- It's confirmed.
They brought a Bundt cake.
- High-ranking officers.
What the hell are they doing here?
- Book club.
(footsteps)
- Ah, my posse.
- Let the cookie exchange begin.
- Hey, wait, I don't want
to sit next to Pinochet.
- A couple of dictators
brought dictator friends
so they had to put in the leaf.
- Time to plan the NATO picnic.
- Gentlemen, I'm so glad
that you considered my house
a suitable place for this summit meeting.
- Though I wish you'd told me.
- I'm going to leave you
now to make your decision.
- Who want's what on your pizza?
- Do you believe what he's wearing?
(stage whispers)
- Hope you brought swim
trunks, heh, heh, heh.
(door slams)
- [Man] Seems strange that we
don't know anything about him.
He's not in our file.
- Quite. Besides being a charming host
what credentials can
this Mr. Kobras offer us?
He's unknown to our services as well.
- That means he's not compromised.
- No one else wore a cape.
- He managed to elude our security,
which means he's so smart he can do it.
- That's a distorted way of reasoning.
- Is it distorted to ask
why this summit meeting
of the heads of state
of the entire world--
- (Imitates Inspector
Clouseau) My minky is here.
- Must be held on private property?
- It's customary to hold
this kind of meeting in
reserved and selected locations.
Everything becomes less formal.
It's not the first time.
- But does this mansion
offer sufficient guarantees?
- It's so great that they
wanna see my cabaret act.
- I better get my wiener
wraps out of the oven.
- She does her roots
black for some reason.
(bell sounds, mechanical noise)
- Wienie.
- They used to have a
carny running that ride,
but the salary got too much.
(noise stops)
- This will take a little bit,
I'm still installing Windows.
- Do you guys like North Korea?
I sure don't.
- I'll use my powers of looking.
- (Tom gasps) There's
another meeting over there!
- Goldfinger got Mike Tyson!
- No!
(strange noises)
- The Botany 500-man.
- Uh-oh, they left the
meeting on too long.
- Now he sees through a glass, dumbly.
- (deep voice) Shimmy shimmy,co-co
bop, shimmy shimmy bop.
- We're all agreed then,
Carrot-top is the best comic.
- Yes, much better than Yahoo Serious.
- Are they trying to resell this
as a Hallmark Christmas Special,
one that didn't get a
theatrical release, you know?
- (Sighs) Well, I'm just
gonna go get our water.
- Fine, gentlemen.
We can go home.
You will receive further
instructions at the proper time.
- This was great, we should
do it again sometime,
great to see you guys, let's
take the scenic road, bye.
(buzzing)
- I've run out of quarters.
- The men who control the destiny
of the world will be here.
- Barry Diller, here?
- When the world is
mine, I alone will decide
whether it is to be war
or peace, life or death.
- Stuffing or potatoes.
- According to the new order
which I shall establish.
- Hey, did the Plantagenets
have a burning permit?
- They immediately slap Molly
Hatchett in the tape deck.
- You will never again leave me
for this irrational feeling you call love.
I have an assignment for you.
Tony Farms is the Pyoo-ma-man.
- Poo-ma-man.
- The Pumaman is my enemy.
- Whoever is my enemy
is your enemy as well.
He must die.
- Anyway, toes on the
line, look up a little.
- He must die, and you shall
be the one to kill him.
(strange noises)
When he comes looking for
you, greet him, smile at him.
- Buy him a beer.
- But you will be ready.
Take this gun.
- I've got plenty, I'll
never use it, please take it.
- When he comes near you, shoot him.
- Can I do it tomorrow?
I have nail wraps scheduled.
- Kill him!
Finish him off!
- But funny things on him!
Show people his butt!
- It will be the greatest act of love.
- So go to Stewart Anderson's
with him, then sleep with him,
got it.
- Is this a Glock I see before me?
- It will be an act of
love from you to me.
Do you understand me?
- Or am I talking to my heads, here, what?
- Hey, a statue of Whoopie Goldberg.
- Hey, Sondra Locke's gonna
take the direct approach
with Clint.
- The slack-wearing superhero.
- Now, careful, you're
gonna clip one of the heads.
(Jane cries out)
- ♫Love to love you, baby ♫
(gunshot)
(Tom makes Donald Duck noise)
(Jane cries out)
- I can fly two miles an hour.
- Tony, run!
- Constantly-Out-Of-His-League-Man.
- His fortress of Balditude.
- Laserium, featuring the
music of Donald Pleasence.
(Tony screams)
- He's the kind of guy
who'd stick his tongue
on a frozen flagpole twice.
(Tony screams)
- Yeah, he just can't
like his book pow-ell.
- Oh, blew a breaker, someone
must be using the toaster.
- Stop! Your powers
are worn out! Finished!
- Done! Completed!
- Threadbare! Shiny at the elbows!
- You cannot escape me, Pyoo-ma-man!
- POO-MA-MAN!
Oh, is that right, Dee-on-ald?
- You're just a small,
insignificant human being--
- That's hoo-man being, oh, no ...
- I'm supposed to come up with
a snappy retort and I can't.
- This is where the little
elevator really pays off.
(strange noises)
(theme music)
- Are you leaning on
the switch over there?
(upbeat music)
- The door is like two steps to the right.
- Man, one of those
prefab English castles.
- Uh, Puma, honey, if
you keep your legs up,
you'll go faster.
- Tony Farms.
- Raises soybeans.
- You must obey me.
- At all times he has the look of a man
who's been hit with a fish.
- I will destroy your powers.
- Oh, no, he, wo--oh, ho,
lookout, oh, Mrs. English lady!
I'm trying to fly, go
backwards, okay, okay,
woah-ho-ho, god, woah!
- I will destroy your mind.
- I will bunch up your package
so it's very uncomfortable.
- I got a new jacket.
- You belong to me now.
- I have the title to your head.
- You cannot escape me!
- There go my keys, my
wallet, and my camera.
- You can no longer jump into space.
- Look out below, half digested
fish and chips coming down.
- Okay, okay, I got it.
- (Tom makes noises)
- Because you are made of earth!
- Corn grows in you.
- And to earth you shall return.
- That's kind of an odd
thing to say, even for him.
- And there goes the 25
million dollar restoration
of Westminster Abbey.
- He lost his inherent
puma tuck-pointing skills.
- Pumaman!
- Oh, look, he's refenestrating.
(funky music)
- Do the Hustle!
- If I can get up there in
time I can push him out.
- One--
- Pumaman!
- [Vadinho] Don't let yourself go, Tony!
Resist!
- Try and fall, is that what you said?
- Two--
- Pumaman's friend.
- First save me, then change me.
- Tony Farms.
- He has forty acres.
- Your body no longer belongs to you.
The forces of the cosmos
have turned you over to me.
(crunching sound)
- Are the heads eating potato chips?
- Come back to me!
I order you to return!
- Mach schnell!
- I am waiting for you!
(Tony screams)
- I'm back on catnip,
man, you gotta help me!
- Help me, Vadinho!
He's calling me!
Can you hear him, can you hear him?
I can't fight it!
- Calm yourself!
(Tony screams)
- I can't, I've got to go!
- Chewing the scenery.
- If you go, you're lost!
They'll kill you!
You must resist!
Repeat with me, "Each man is a god.
"Each man is free."
Do not think of anything else.
Concentrate!!
Repeat, repeat with me,
- - With me.
- Each man is a god.
Each man is free.
Each man is a god.
- Each man is a god.
- Each man is free.
- Each man is a weenie.
- Each man is a god.
- Each man is free.
- Each man is a puss, okay.
- (cracking noise)
- These walnuts are good.
- Mr. Forbes is here if
you wanna go for a ride.
- I've taken away his powers.
- So that's done, anyway.
- And his will is broken.
But he's putting up an
unexpected resistance.
- I'll take care of it.
- Comb the area, find him!
And don't make any noise.
I don't want any trouble around here.
- 'Cause the police would
find out I'm pirating cable.
- I'll break a few more
wills before lunch,
then meet some (inaudible) on Friday.
- Pyoo-ma-man.
- Poo-ma-man, boy!
Pumaman, I am ordering you--
(cracking noise)
I am ordering you--
- A fajita, is that okay?
- To kill yourself.
- John-boy Walton!
- I like the other head better.
- It's all right, Vadinho.
It's over.
- Oh, great! So can we go, Mike?
- No.
- Damn.
- Listen, I want you to hear my epitaph.
- "I'm with stupid."
- He wasn't much in his
life, either as a man,
or a Pumaman.
And now he's worth absolutely nothing.
- The same as when he was alive.
- That is not true.
You are a worthy man.
- Worthy of a beating.
- You will be all right.
- Only if I lose a habit.
- Which one?
- Nose-picking? Public farting?
- Wanting to live!!
- Gotta clock these windows, quick!
- Let's only be a big,
giant baby, (crying)
- Oh, let me go!
- I just wanna help you die
with a modicum of dignity!
- When you die you don't suffer any more!
You don't have a master!
- You must fight back, brother!
For you, for me, for Jane!
As for all who want to live free!
Listen to me.
Perhaps there is a way.
Only ten minutes but you can do it.
Go to a deep sleep, a false death!
Ten minutes with no life.
It is in your power.
- Well, I'm just sore, is all.
- Kobras does not know it.
He cannot take it from you.
- Please get off, I'm
feeling funny "down there."
- Hold your breath.
Your heartbeat can slow down.
- I just have to not wiggle.
- Diminish.
- I mean, anybody would feel this, right?
It's natural, right?
- Stop.
- So pumas are suicidally
depressive mouth-breathers?
- We show you now the general
vicinity of the heart.
- That is right, Tony.
Let yourself go.
- Stop working out.
- You are dead, you are dead
for all, even for Kobras.
(quiet music)
- Duhhhhhhh, okay.
(doors clanging)
- Hey, look what we made, Mike.
- Why that looks like a--
why that looks for all
the world like a replica
of the head of Roger Whittaker.
- We made it with our genuine Aztec mask.
- Wow, that's great.
You know, I can hear him sing right now.
♫ I left my ship out in the harbor ♫
I assume you gained control
of his mind and his will.
- There's no other reason I
can think of to own a replica
of the head of Roger Whittaker.
- Yeah, exactly.
- But I have to ask why.
Why Roger Whittaker?
Why not, say, Barbara Feldon?
- Feldon?
Right, we thought of that, okay, Mike?
And Sting and Chipmunk
and Senator John Warner.
- And Puff Daddy and Al
Checchi and Webb Pierce
and Judy Carne and Joan Sutherland.
- And George Lindsay and Barbara Bush.
- And people like that.
And Mike, when you only
have time to effectively
control one person--
- We have other things to do, Mike.
- Then Roger Whittaker
is the perfect choice.
Take our word for it.
It's who we got, now what
do you wanna do with him?
- Well, I can't think of anything at all.
- Use your imagination, man!
It's Roger Whittaker!
That means songs, sure, but he
can probably do other things,
you know, light typing and filing.
And maybe you need help
with your hand-washing.
- No, no I don't.
Frankly, I think it's a waste of time.
- Oh, fine, we go to all this trouble,
hand Mike Roger Whittaker,
and he drops the ball.
- Here's what we all-- here's Mike,
"Duhhh, what do I do with this?"
You can just go on with your
Roger Whittaker-free life,
you poor sap, but the
next time you need to hear
"Durham Town," you're
on your own, good luck!
- Remember, though, we
control Roger Whittaker.
- That's right.
- So watch your back!
Roger Whittaker could
be on you at any moment.
- There he is!
- Woahh!
- I'm kidding, this time.
- Yeah, look at him run!
We'll be right back, everybody.
In the meantime be on the
lookout for Roger Whittaker.
(sinister lauging)
(theme music)
- There he is, Roger Whittaker!
- I'm scared.
- Oh, I overdid it on the Fancy Feast.
- Later, Ma Barker and the
gang come to finish him off.
Tee-hee, tee-hee.
- They're here and the
cupcakes are still in the oven!
- Friends are visiting for MURDER!
(doors slam)
- Pumaman!
- It's Cliff Claven! Hey, Cliffy!
- So let's cut his ears and paws off,
we get the fifty buck bounty.
- So tense right here.
- Tee-hee, tee-hee.
- Shh!
- Tee-hee.
- Tell Santa I love him.
- He won't get my Amontillado.
- He's had it.
- Chicken pox.
You won't catch it from us.
- So anyway, do you have a new modem?
- We found him.
He's committed suicide.
Shall I put a bullet in
him, just to be sure.
- No, that would be cheating.
- No, it has to look like
an unfortunate accident.
But be sure that he's dead.
- You can count on it, sir.
- Boss says I'm in charge
and I get your lunch today
and you drive.
- Can't you just accept it, Tom.
- I don't know, I just, I don't know.
- Tee-hee.
- Why do I have to stay in the car?
- We couldn't find a corpse
more dead than this one.
- What are you gonna do with the body?
- Leave him like he is.
- Are they gone, oh!
I have slacks like that.
- No, see, this was just really avoidable.
- I was alive for a second,
now I'm dead again, go away.
- Why don't you shoot him?
- Because Kobras said not to.
- You are so Kobra-whipped, man.
- I'm just thinking
about the last dead guy
who sprang up and killed half our men.
- Ooh, it seems like I have
you in a bit of a bind,
don't I, Mr. Dead Human?
(makes buzzing noise)
- Hate to see you sneeze
right now. (buzzing noise)
- Here's the deal, I don't make you sneeze
and you give me your poop
for the rest of your life.
- Even when dead his hair looks terrific.
- I just have a really
hard time making decisions,
you know, you guys.
- Pumaman!
- I feel good about our decision, I do.
But let's go back!
No, no forget it.
- Certainly this is a victory for good.
- You've succeeded!
They think you're dead.
And now they will leave you alone.
- To be left alone, the
goal of every great hero.
- But what about the mask?
- Forget it.
You are only a man, now.
You cannot do it.
- Did I say man?
You're not a man, more like a box turtle.
I'm getting outta here.
- Do I get to keep the cape?
- I'm finally gonna get my
pennies counted, anyway.
- And that dynamite is
for that bastard Kobras?
- I said forget it.
- And should I also forget Jane?
And the fact that Kobras
wants to take over the world?
- (Crow whines) And
should I also forget Jane?
- (inaudible) gods have abandoned us.
Or perhaps they want sacrifice.
- What sacrifice?
- My life.
- You want to destroy Kobras
with a suicide action?
There's got to be another way.
- Kobras has the police
and all those who command
in his power.
- Little doobage for later.
- I must go.
- Why you?
- I am the High Priest.
I am responsible.
And if the death of one man can save many,
that death is right.
- The death of two men is just as right.
- Let go of my death.
- You have no power now.
And there's no reason for you to pay.
- I have a personal reason.
- But the price is too high.
You don't come.
- Damned hardhead! Stop giving orders!
I won't let you go alone.
- You are right, brother.
- Orville or Wilbur?
- I ask you to forgive me.
But you don't come.
- Try and stop me.
- I ask you to forgive me.
- Forgive you what?
- I've been seeing another superhero.
(Vadinho sighs)
- Ka-boom!
- Yes! The Aztec speaks for all of us!
(sentimental music)
- Say hello to the nice people, Pumaman.
- (High voice) Hello, people.
- Mmm-let me out, let me out,
you have no right to do this.
I'm Pumaman.
- I've gotta deliver this
ham, and then I'll leave.
- Oh, wait, it's back there.
What the hell--
- Aztec drove to Wisconsin,
scored some M-80s.
- The kids are gonna love Easter morning.
- Oh, man, we got Aztecs.
- Hold up where you are or I'll kill you!
- I've got a Members Only jacket.
- Shoot, and everything
will blow up for a mile
in all directions.
- Oh, didn't have quite
the impact I was hoping.
- Tell Kobras I want to speak to him.
- Forget it, I'm never gonna
get through for Yanni tickets!
(machines humming)
- All right, Craig T.
Nelson, make me laugh.
(static)
- It's an Aztec family Christmas.
- What do you want?
- The gold mask.
- With your face sweat cleaned out.
- I'm sure we could reach
some sort of agreement.
Lead him into the Great Hall.
Treat him like an honored guest.
I'll join you.
- Woah, big Aztec.
- So, what about Montezuma, nice guy, or--
- Tony's alive.
- Don't eat saliva, why
would I even think of it?
- That was an odd series of smells.
(funky music)
- Do the Hustle!
Come on, do the Hustle.
- Ooh, and you put butter under my skin,
pushed cloves of garlic in, hmm.
- Oh, my cat's cradle got
out of control. (sobs)
- I'm going to try to
control the recycling guy,
'cause I didn't sort my
stuff very good this month.
- Do you have a Great
little boy's room here?
- Step forward.
(ethereal music)
- Now spin around, let me see
how those slacks fit in the back.
- Space--
- What a strange Department
of Motor Vehicles.
- Who are you?
Why do you want the mask?
- In order to be smokin'!
- Each man is a god.
- Don't ever do that again.
- Each man is free.
Each man is a god.
- So if each man is a god,
where does that leave the gods?
- Each man is free.
- Look, he didn't ask
for your yearbook quote.
- Yes, yes, indeed, you are free.
- Each man is free.
- You're free to obey me.
You cannot escape my will, nor resist me.
- Yeah, gotta agree with him on that one.
- I can make you wobble.
- Obey me.
- Each man is free.
- How about guys in
jail, they're not free?
How about guys in gulags?
- Each man is free.
- Ah, let him go, boss.
He's so sincere.
- I gotta drill some
eyeholes closer together
in this thing, it's so annoying.
- Each man is free.
Each man is free.
- Take those explosives from your body.
- Little Orphan Aztec.
- Don't do it!
- He went to the barber and said,
"Give me a haircut like Mary Gross."
- Peek-a-boo, peek-a-boo!
- Hand them to the person next to you.
- On which side, does
it matter, either one?
- You know, at some point
the world has gotta stop
letting idiots like this
almost take it over.
- Carefully.
- I also got some bottle
rockets in my socks.
- That's right.
- That's good, baby.
- So, basically, the hero is
this guy, I think it's time
we faced that fact.
(glass shattering)
- Oh, no, the Reader's
Digest Condensed Books.
(theme music)
- Oh, Joe Theismann's
really hurt this time.
- Man, I am having phantom
pains like you wouldn't believe.
- I wonder if my girlfriend
would do that for me?
- You're kind of weird, Mike.
(crashing noise)
- Where's the candy?
(Tony shouts)
- Must run farther away from the danger!
- A medicine ball!
Oh, no, it's Donald Pleasence.
- Wow, each man as in
punching bag, I guess.
- Each man is Jerry Quarry.
(sings to the tune of "Kung
Fu Fighting) ♫ Everybody was
♫ Aztec fighting ♫
(upbeat music)
- Ah, great. You know, I've
got it, don't worry yourself.
- A cantaloupe.
Oh, it's him.
- Phrenologists.
- So it turns into a good
old Hal Needham movie.
- ♫ Dick's Renault selection and service ♫
- ♫ Snyder Drug, we're busting up prices ♫
- You know, I have almost
no respect for pumas now.
I now know that if I ever run into a puma
I can just push it the hell over.
(inaudble)
- Keep playing back there.
- ♫ When you want the
flavor of bacon in a dip ♫
- I wish Poaching-Protected-Species-Man
would show up
and take care of this scene.
- You could call Ted-Nugent-Man.
- I can't get it out of first.
- Take that, members of Boston.
- Hey, Vadinho, you gotta
try this, it's fun, whee!
(upbeat music)
- Hey, it's Archie Rice-Man.
- Jump wall.
♫ Believe it or not this movie's still on
♫ it should have ended two hours ago ♫
- Is that Donald Pleasence?
I wanna get his autograph.
(mechanical noises)
- Beyond Donalddome.
- Yes, pumas have instinctive knowledge
of wiring and home construction.
- Grr. I'm a deadly puma,
be frightened of me.
- I didn't think he'd sink that low.
- Olly, olly, oxen free.
- I'll give him a Purple
Herman and then a Jock Lock--
- Don't ever mention Donald's jock again.
- May I borrow a cup of BALD?
- Please, know I had a terrible childhood.
- I'll harm you.
(inaudible)
- You will drop your pants to your ankles
and walk through town saying,
"I am a ninny."
- Oh, make sure you set it on "bald."
- Don't jiggle.
Mom wants a nice picture for Christmas.
(mechanical noises)
- Oh, excuse me.
- Boy, time to call
semi-competent Aztec man again.
- Would you look at this
beautiful hardwood floor
they covered up?
- There's a layer of nougat in this house.
- I'm sensing danger, no, it's mildew.
- Perhaps now would be a good time
to jump around like an idiot!
- Castles are nice, but they're not big
on livable basement space.
- Wool-Over-His-Eyes-Man.
- Easily-Bamboozled-Man.
- Three-Steps-Behind-Man.
- You know, world, get used to being
run by Donald Pleasence.
(gunfire)
- Guess he sensed danger there.
- This is Flying Officer Donald Pleasence
with the traffic report.
- Between sessions of
staring into the wigs
he became an accomplished pilot.
- Oops, missed him, better
go home, I did what I could.
- A peach--Oh, that's Donald Pleasence.
- Breathtaking London!
(upbeat music)
♫ The fat-free yoghurt,
it's not short on flavor♫
- It's all over, Kobras.
- Bryan Timothy Kobras, you
land this helicopter right now!
- Bending metals doors, no problem.
Subduing stocky senior
citizens, that's another story.
- Oh, it got hard, bye.
- Oh, the network shouldn't have bought
Kelsey Grammar a helicopter.
(explosion)
- ♫ Burn an old man,
singe all his flesh off ♫
- Well, then, the gods
fulfilled their holy plan
to roast a man in a helicopter.
- (Deep voice) Thank you, pasta necklace.
- Oh, man, this thing is really rank.
- Croquet courts of the gods.
- Hey, Vidalia, would you
mind worshipping for us?
I think we're just gonna get going.
- The evil has been defeated.
Their portection has not failed.
- I did most of it.
- Do they also protect couples in love?
- Respect!
- Places like this were created
by them to make contact.
- And other cold remedies.
- Kneel!
- Look, I told you, my names, Tony.
Man, I thought we were
getting close--oh, I see.
- Man, get a room!
- Oh, holy salt lick.
- You know, if the
Spaceman-puma thing turns out
to be the correct religion,
I, for one, will be very surprised.
(majestic music)
- Yay, sky, there's a
place where there's sky!
- This is indeed a blessed day.
- Hm, it would be fun to take
a three-wheeler up there.
- The air is pretty.
- So these three are the
only ones stupid enough
to let the spacemen play with them.
- The rain's gonna totally
frizz out my hair for our date.
- Stonehenge is a chain?
- Apparently.
- Uh, hi, uh, say, did anyone see a mask?
- Your regular god was
busy, so he sent me instead.
- It was the second amulet
kiss that got him here.
- Zap.
- You know sometimes the
gods make extra money
giving people rides.
- Ah, you guys took me seriously, suckers!
- We're just gonna toss
it on another planet
and see who bites.
- The gods, eh, (laughs) the gods.
- Oh, crap, it's that Aztec guy.
- The whole Bible thing, bunch of hooey.
It's all about aliens and spinning globes.
- They are pleased with you up there.
- I mean, I didn't tell them everything.
- But I'm not happy with them down here.
What's going to happen to the mask?
- Hey, who the hell is
that little pipsqueak?
- They are taking it back to its temple
in the Andes mountains.
- Where some other villain will take it.
- And I'm going with them.
- Does that mean you're
gonna disappear, too?
- Eh, they're gonna whack me.
- Tell me the truth, Vidinho.
Are you one of them?
- Me, no, I'm Jewish.
- We all are, a bit.
But if you want to see me again.
- Don't.
- When you are the father
of a small Pumaman,
take him to the plateau.
- And drop him off.
- I will teach him the powers.
- I'll give you a good rate,
'cause you're good people.
- Goodbye, brother.
- Goodbye, sister.
- Honor it.
- Little titty-twister from the gods.
- Don't worry.
- Goodbye, Pumaman.
- Is there anything I
should tell the people
about truth and beauty?
- No, I don't think so.
- Should we love each other?
- Nah, don't worry about it.
- ♫ The Pyoo-may-man,
there's only you in my life ♫
- Keep your catbox clean, my friend.
Watch our for urinary tract infections.
So long!
- Yeah, only the gods
could produce something
as beautiful as that.
- If this is all the gods can do,
I'm over to the dark side so fast.
- Goodbye, the Pyoo-May-man,
carry on your tradition
of flying clumsily with
your rear-end in the air.
- And we hear the dim
cry of an anal probe.
- You know what, I
never liked your friend,
and I don't want him at our wedding.
- Uh, there's no afterlife, sorry.
- The bodies of six gods
were found after their
ship crashed into a mountain
just outside London.
- Jane, tell me it wasn't a dream.
- You can prove it for yourself.
Jump!
- Might as well, jump!
- Ready, here we go!
- Jeez, I wouldn't trust this guy
to hold a door open for me.
(Jane laughs)
- You've got fly me over to Bennigan's
so I can show Sherry.
- Now I'm going to dig my
spurs into your hindquarters.
- I've never seen anybody
make love in the air.
- But that's how you make little Pumamen.
- He immediately defiles
the holy gift given to him.
- ♫ Now they're going to boff in the air ♫
- ♫ Now there's only you in my life ♫
- (laughs) Would you stop?
(upbeat music)
- Starring the Gambino
family and some English guy.
- Theology contained within this picture
may not be wholly accurate.
Consult your doctor before embarking
on a theology program.
- And remember to buy a
Pumaman catbox filler.
Less dust, better clumping.
- Yep, this is music to praise the gods,
that's for sure.
- ♫ Glory to our space
gods in the highest ♫
(Tom continues singing)
- Mike, this movie just tears it for me,
I'm gonna resign.
Yeah, I quit, I'll see you around.
- I don't think you can do that.
- Oh, I can do that.
- It's not over yet, Crow, Crow?
(Tom continues singing)
- Would you cut that out!
Stop that!
(doors clanging)
- (imitating Donald Pleasence)
Roger Whittaker, obey.
- Well, here it is, I'm officially
tendering my resignation.
- Okay, wow, looks very professional.
- Stop trying to talk
me out of this, Mike,
I've made up my mind.
- Obey.
- Who knows, maybe
somewhere out there is a guy
who's forced to watch
good movies. (laughs)
Well, so long fellas, it's
really been a good ride.
- Okay, we'll see you, then.
- Hey everyone, I'm back!
Hey, the place looks great!
Hey, how are you guys?
- Good.
- You know, I'm freelance now
and it's really going good.
Say, any chance you have
something here for me?
- Well, uh, right now
there's only part-time
and you won't get benefits.
- Oh, fine, fine, fine. Phew!
Woah, I'm employed again.
Man, what a stressful
episode in my life that was!
Ooh, I don't know how I survived.
- I didn't even know you left.
- Hey, we better check on Pearl.
How's the ball going, Pearl?
- Ball, schmall, nobody came except Bobo
and he's snapped his
tether and joined Brain Guy
and the 70 other people
who just showed up.
(party noises)
Just listen to that.
How's this gonna look
to my ghostly ancestors?
Isn't there anybody up there
who can give me a break
just this once?
- ♫ Oh, I don't believe in if any more ♫
- Could it be?
- Hello, Pearl!
- Mellow folk sensation Roger Whittaker!
How did you get here?
- Well, I sailed in and left my ship
♫ out in the harbor ♫
- Oh, Roger, you've
saved my ancestral ball.
- Well, I'm glad to.
♫ For you are beautiful ♫
- Roger, join me in my evil plans.
- Well, I'd love to, Pearl, but
♫ tomorrow for old England she sails ♫
- Yes, perfect!
You sail to England,
contact all your henchmen,
Glenn Yarbrough, Pete
Seeger, the Kingston Trio,
and I will assemble an
army of aging folk singers,
and together we will--
the hell do you think you're going?
- But, Pearl, they're
singing Asia songs in there.
- One more move and
you're dead, Whittaker.
- Ha, ha! ♫ I have no fear of death,
♫ it brings no sorrow ♫
- Oh, yeah! Fear this, you bearded freak!
(crunching and clanging)
(majestic theme music)